ARCHANA H NAIR

(+ 45 71451513

x archana.harinair@gmail.com

in linkedin.com/in/archana-h-nair-0b64992a/

github.com/archana6832

archana6832.github.io/portfolio-website/

O Copenhagen , Denmark

SUMMARY

Full stack web developer with a background in Engineering teaching and mentoring. Experienced in mentoring more than 15 groups of students in their Engineering final year projects and teaching more than 500 students throughout the career. Competent in creating websites and applications from concept, layout and interactive elements to server-side and databases. Skilled in the latest practices in web development (HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, NodeJS).

SKILLS

Front End Development

- -HTML, CSS, JavaScript, TypeScript
- -Libraries / Frameworks (React, Redux, Angular, Material, Bootstrap, SASS/SCSS, jQuery)
- -Responsive design, modals and touch interaction
- -AJAX & JSON
- -Version Control (Git)
- -unit testing, integration testing, acceptance testing, and end-to-end testing)
- -Mobile Apps (React Native, Expo, PWA)

Back End Development

- -NodeJS & Express
- -APIs (JSON, RESTful, Postman)
- -Hosting & Web Services (AWS, Google, Firestore, Heroku, Netlify)
- -Relational & non-relational databases (PostgreSQL, MongoDB)

EDUCATION

CareerFoundry

Full-Stack Development Program April 2021 - Feb 2022 <u>View Program</u>

Speak School of Danish

Danish Language Leanring June 2018 - Dec 2019 B2 -Advanced Level <u>View Program</u>

T K M College Of Engineering

Masters in Engineering & Technology August 2012 - Oct 2014 Second Rank in University View Program

WEB DEVELOPMENT PROJECTS

CareerFoundry Project- Meet app (Jan 2022)

- Developed a progressive-web application with React using a test-driven development (TDD) technique with Enzyme and Jest.
- Translated user stories into scenarios for unit testing, integration testing, acceptance testing (Cucumber) and end-to-end testing(Puppeteer)
- Implemented serverless functions with AWS lambda to authenticate and authorize users. **GitHub Repo**

CareerFoundry Project - Chat App (Feb 2022)

- Developed a chat app for mobile devices using React Native.
- Used Gifted Chat library to create the chat interface and its functionality and Android Studio's Virtual Device to manually view and test the app.
- Used Google Firestore Database to store chat conversations and Google Firebase authentication to authenticate users anonymously.
 GitHub Repo

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Managing Partner Dec 2014 - Feb 2018 **Fashion Jewellers and Textiles**

- Managed day to day operations of the store and ensured management satisfaction.
- Achieved improved sales by maintaining collections that are trendy and classy.
- Assured better customer satisfaction by listening to customers and implementing their suggestions.

Assistant Professor May 2010 - Nov 2011 **Atharva College of Engineering, Mumbai, India**

- Planned teaching methodologies effectively and assured 85% passing yearly.
- Mentored students in their projects and ensured the submission on time.
- Assisted Head of Department, achieved better performance of students by introducing new teaching plan.